<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Green Lighting Wholesale - News</title>
  <updated>2018-08-13T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Green Lighting Wholesale</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/price-increase-and-projected-ustr-tariff-impacts</id>
    <published>2018-08-13T10:32:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-08-13T10:40:51-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/price-increase-and-projected-ustr-tariff-impacts"/>
    <title>Price increase and projected USTR tariff impacts</title>
    <author>
      <name>Brett Clark</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table width="600">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p> </p>
<table width="600">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="87">
<p><strong>Date:</strong></p>
</td>
<td width="499">
<p>August 13, 2018</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="87">
<p><strong>To</strong>:</p>
</td>
<td width="499">
<p>Acuity Brands Distributors</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="87">
<p><strong>Subject:</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Price increase and projected USTR tariff impacts<br>  </p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><br> <br> <br> Over the last several months, our business has been greatly affected by cost increases on many fronts, including commodities (such as steel), certain electronic components, transportation and wage inflation. In addition, we have experienced higher costs from tariffs implemented by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), and anticipate additional costs resulting from proposed tariffs. As such, we are announcing the following:<br>  </p>
<ol>
<li>A price <strong>increase of up to 6% on the majority of all lighting and lighting control products will be effective September 17, 2018.</strong> Specific category increases will be shared in subsequent communications through your Acuity agency sales representative. The last day for entry and release of orders at current prices is September 14, 2018. All orders after this date will be invoiced at the new prices. Committed projects that cannot be released for immediate shipment on or before September 14, 2018 will need to be re-submitted to Acuity for review.<br>  </li>
<li>Government-imposed tariffs impacting Chinese components and finished goods will require us to pass on these costs through additional, proportional price increases on impacted products sold by Acuity Brands.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Section 301 tariffs covering more than $34B in Chinese imports went into effect on July 6<sup>th</sup> with an additional list for $16B of imports that will go into effect on August 23<sup>rd</sup>. These tariffs are expected to impact the cost of future material supply.</li>
<li>Additional tariffs on approximately $200B in Chinese-produced components and finished goods are planned, which will have a significant cost impact if implemented. <br> <br> We are currently evaluating the impact of these tariffs across our product offering, and we will continue to keep you updated in the coming weeks on additional tariff-related increases.</li>
</ul>
<p>We remain committed to supporting our industry partners as we all work to grow together through these difficult market challenges. As you know, Acuity Brands has invested heavily in our strategic partnerships, and we will continue to be a partner as we work through these difficult market challenges.<br>  <br> Best Regards,</p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="33%"></td>
<td width="33%"></td>
<td width="33%"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="33%">
<p>Sero Cardamone<br> SVP, Global Sales</p>
</td>
<td width="33%">
<p>Amra Boucher<br> VP, Customer Engagement</p>
</td>
<td width="33%">
<p>Mike DeBlois<br> VP, Pricing Operations</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/business-that-do-lighting-retrofits-could-qualify-for-0-60-a-square-foot-tax-credit</id>
    <published>2018-02-08T14:13:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-08T14:20:23-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/business-that-do-lighting-retrofits-could-qualify-for-0-60-a-square-foot-tax-credit"/>
    <title>Business that do lighting retrofits could qualify for $0.60 a Square Foot tax credit</title>
    <author>
      <name>Brett Clark</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">A one year retroactive 2017 EPAct extension is looking very positive for this week.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b2/United_States_Capitol_-_west_front.jpg" alt="" width="147" height="75"></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">This means Business that do lighting retrofits could <strong>qualify for $0.60 a Square Foot tax credit</strong>. Yes you have heard that right. Yesterday, the Senate introduced their 2018 Budget Bill, titled <strong>"<a href="http://www.energytaxsavers.com/sendy/l/LDdDLgmNPYdK892W763sWtT6Hw/mR892SqGqGvcxFI5892yxEXTPw/O763w72uZRZu165iQmoICYzw" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.energytaxsavers.com/sendy/l/LDdDLgmNPYdK892W763sWtT6Hw/mR892SqGqGvcxFI5892yxEXTPw/O763w72uZRZu165iQmoICYzw&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1518201678933000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEGanl7bO_2zm0a0GSBTDm0vlYCqA">Bipartisan Budget Act of 2018</a></strong>". This bill is the Senate's version of the budget which needs to be passed before<span> </span><span data-term="goog_1823471951">midnight</span><span data-term="goog_1823471952">tonight</span>, <span data-term="goog_1823471953">2/8/18</span>, and it includes a one-year retroactive extension of EPAct 179D for projects completed through 12/31/17. It just needs to be passed by the Senate and House. This is by no means official, as the House could reject it or other issues could create another shutdown and a revised bill. However, we should have something official by<span> </span><span data-term="goog_1823471954">tomorrow </span>morning.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As soon as possible, we recommend beginning to compile information on any of your potentially eligible projects completed in 2017 so you can fit the EPAct benefit on your 2017 tax returns. This would include any newly constructed or renovated commercial or government buildings completed in 2017. </p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Visit www.appropriations.senate.gov to find out more</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/17145473-green-lighting-wholesale-recognized-by-aep-ohio-for-top-10-performance-for-2014</id>
    <published>2015-03-06T14:48:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-19T10:19:37-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/17145473-green-lighting-wholesale-recognized-by-aep-ohio-for-top-10-performance-for-2014"/>
    <title>Green Lighting Wholesale Recognized by AEP Ohio for Top 10 Performance for 2014</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ally Starr</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/aepoh_logo_small.png?9461542711698274810"></strong></p>
<p><strong>Green Lighting Wholesale was recently recognized by AEP Ohio for our energy efficiency efforts!!</strong></p>
<p>AEP released the following:</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em>AEP Ohio’s Energy Efficiency program recognizes Green Lighting Wholesale as one of the top ten performing distributors for the 2014 Energy Efficiency program. Working as a Solution Provider with AEP Ohio, they are able to assist AEP Ohio business customers and contractors with installation of energy efficiency lighting and provide support on program applications.  </em></span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em>“Green Lighting ranked 10th out of hundreds of solution providers which shows their hard work and commitment to the program”, said Angie Rybalt, AEP Ohio Solution Provider Channel Coordinator. </em></span></strong></p>
<p>Not only do we provide you with energy efficient lighting, we provide it to you at a price no one can compete with. Our goal is to better the environment, supply our customers with the best product on the market, and to save our customers financially.</p>
<p><strong>Green Lighting Wholesale will continue it's commitment to provide YOU with energy efficient lighting. <br></strong></p>
<p>What is  AEP's Energy Efficiency Program?</p>
<p>When you purchase or replace your old lighting with energy efficient lighting, AEP offers incentive programs to customers <span id="ctl00_cphContent_GlobalUserControl2">for the installation of these energy efficient products. </span><span id="ctl00_cphContent_GlobalUserControl2">This program helps reduce the cost of your investment and creates a</span><strong><span id="ctl00_cphContent_GlobalUserControl2"> long-term reduction in your energy consumption and costs.</span></strong></p>
<p>Some eligible businesses include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Agriculture</li>
<li>Construction &amp; Major Renovation</li>
<li>Data Centers</li>
<li>Government &amp; Non-profit</li>
<li>Grocery &amp; Convenience stores</li>
<li>Hospitals &amp; Health Care</li>
<li>Manufacturing &amp; Warehousing</li>
<li>Office Buildings</li>
<li>Retail</li>
<li>Schools &amp; Universities</li>
<li>Small Business</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span id="ctl00_cphContent_GlobalUserControl2"></span>What are you waiting for? Call us today, and let us show you how much money we can save you!! <br></strong></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/16538521-increase-your-cattle-barn-profits</id>
    <published>2015-02-12T09:18:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-16T10:54:34-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/16538521-increase-your-cattle-barn-profits"/>
    <title>Increase Your Cattle Barn Profits</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ally Starr</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p>It’s time to upgrade that old dull lighting in your barn. You’re thinking, “No big deal, I have lights and they aren’t broken so why bother”. But you’re actually just tossing money away. <strong>Not only can the lighting improve your energy bills, it can improve the milk production in your cattle.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>That’s right! <strong>More light = More milk</strong>. It’s been proven that the more light a cow receives, the more dormant the melatonin hormone becomes. The light then activates other milk producing hormones. Studies show that increases in milk production can range from 5%-16%, but are most consistently in the 8%-10% range. Do the math, that’s a lot of money!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Contact us today to find the right lighting for your needs! </strong></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/16538825-eastland-career-center-updates-lighting-with-green-lighting-wholesale</id>
    <published>2015-01-19T10:49:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T09:27:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/16538825-eastland-career-center-updates-lighting-with-green-lighting-wholesale"/>
    <title>Eastland Career Center Updates Lighting With Green Lighting Wholesale</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ally Starr</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Green Lighting Wholesale is at it AGAIN! </strong></p>
<p>Check out the difference in this lighting at Eastland Career Center (Groveport, OH).</p>
<p>Before: 400 Watt HPS / After: 4 Lamp T5 HO</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> <img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/Before-After_69a3c9e0-5c9c-446f-a640-90b9b42cab87_large.jpg?924" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Brett Clark, President of Green Lighting Wholesale, and his team swapped out the centers old 400 Watt High Pressure sodium High bays, for 4 Lamp T5 HO High bays. You can buy them <a target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/collections/fluorescent-fixtures/products/4-lamp-t5-fluorescent-high-bay-with-ge-nema-premium-ballast">here</a></p>
<p>As you can see in the before and after pictures, the difference is remarkable. This change instantly opened up the shop the students were learning in, and the lighting is much more bright and white. Not only does this look better, this change is saving the career center money on their energy bills. <strong>These High bays have over a 50% power reduction, and with AEP's Energy Rebates, the Career Center is taking advantage of a 3month ROI.</strong></p>
<p>Does your school or warehouse need a lighting update? Contact us today for a quote.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/15991453-lindsay-honda-press-release</id>
    <published>2014-12-03T15:32:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-12-03T15:33:12-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/15991453-lindsay-honda-press-release"/>
    <title>Lindsay Honda Press Release</title>
    <author>
      <name>Brett Clark</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p>                                                                                         <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/everlast_logo_small.png?859" width="185" height="50" style="float: right;"></p>
<p><strong>NEWS RELEASE</strong></p>
<p>For Immediate Release<br><strong>Lindsay Honda Installs Induction Light Fixtures Across Massive Dealership Parking Lot</strong><br>EverLast® Lighting Exceeds Specification Standards, and Is Used To Replace Nearly 80 Inefficient Metal Halide Fixtures</p>
<p><br>JACKSON, MICHIGAN – December 3rd, 2014 – Lindsay Honda located in Columbus, Ohio, is a new car Honda dealer selling various Honda automotive models, and is home to one of the largest indoor showrooms in the country. Recently, Lindsay Honda partnered with Hawkins Sales of Ohio, and Green Lighting Wholesale, in an effort to seek out a commercial lighting solution that would meet their facility codes while improving illumination, and significantly lowering energy costs. “They wanted the best fixture and technology available on the market at the most cost effective price,” commented Brett Clark, President of Green Lighting Wholesale. As a result, the company decided on EverLast® 200 and 300 watt induction shoe box fixtures.</p>
<p><br>“The fixtures are performing wonderfully. We have had absolutely no issues, and the light output has been fantastic,” explained Clark. The Columbus based dealership replaced nearly 80 of their pre-existing metal halide fixtures across their 180,000 square foot dealership parking lot, and around its facility, in early 2014.</p>
<p><br>In addition, the fixtures qualified for a rebate in excess of $40,000 which was reimbursed to the dealership by American Electric Power of Ohio. “Because Honda is manufactured in Ohio and is a domestic company, the customer was also extremely excited that the fixtures were U.S. made,” explained Clark. “The rebate from American Electric Power was icing on the cake, and aligned with the dealership’s energy efficient vision. After installing the fixtures we had estimated a 60 percent energy reduction across the application.”</p>
<p><br>EverLast® induction light fixtures are 50-70% more energy efficient than metal halides and last up to 100,000 hours, making them virtually maintenance free for up to 15 years. The EverLast® shoe box fixtures provide a more natural and high color rendition light quality unlike traditional metal halide fixtures. “It’s not uncommon for our customers to reap substantial energy savings after installing our lights,” explained Alex Orr, VP of Sales at EverLast® Lighting, Inc. “Furthermore, ROI is one of the most attractive features with our induction lighting technology. Low glare, ease of installation, and our 10 year warranty are all additional reasons that we have had exponential success with parking lot applications.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/Hawkins_logo_small.png?857" width="112" height="146">       <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/ESB-EC-200W_small.jpg?858" width="142" height="142">       <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/8_14_GreenLighting-logo_small.jpg?861" width="112" height="146"></p>
<p>EverLast® Induction lighting fixtures are also available with a dimmable option, providing even more energy savings while areas are vacant.</p>
<p>The EverLast® Shoe Box fixtures are commonly used in surface parking lots and have been installed at locations such as Allegiance Health in Jackson, Michigan, Crippen Auto Mall in Lansing, Michigan, Bryan College in Dayton, Tennessee, and Kelly Chevrolet in Phoenixville, Pennsylvania.<br><br>About EverLast® Lighting: EverLast® Lighting, Inc. is a sister company of Full Spectrum Solutions, Inc. and has quickly grown into the leading manufacturer of energy-efficient lighting solutions for roadway, parking structure, facility and area lighting applications. For additional product information, visit www.everlastlight.com, call 888-383-7578 or send an email to info@everlastlight.com.</p>
<p><br>For press inquiries, contact Kyle Leighton at 517-783-3800 ext.231 or email at kyle@everlastlight.com.</p>
<p><br>If you would like to support EverLast®, please follow EverLast® on Twitter or visit them on Facebook.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/15642357-save-energy-this-winter</id>
    <published>2014-11-12T08:51:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-12T08:51:46-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/blogs/news/15642357-save-energy-this-winter"/>
    <title>Save Energy This Winter</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ally Starr</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>As colder weather is approaching your energy bills are sure to increase. Heating your home increases your energy bills up to 40% according to <a href="http://consumersenergy.com">consumersenergy.com</a>.</p>
<p>Here are some simple ways to save on energy this winter by making a few changes in your lighting.  Whether it is residential or commercial, we have the <span style="color: #38761d;"><strong>GREEN</strong> </span>lighting for you!</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Carefully Choose The Right Light Bulb</strong></span>.</p>
<p>You’d be surprised, how much energy you can save, by choosing from one of these two bulbs.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong></strong><strong> </strong><strong>CFL (Compact Fluorescent Lamps)</strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>These Lamps use one-fifth to one-third the electric power. Spiral-Lite CFLs have a long life of up to 15,000 hours – up to 15 times longer than incandescent light bulbs. What’s best is this LONG life reduces replacement and maintenance costs as well! Check out our affordable CFL <span style="color: #38761d;"><a style="color: #38761d;" title="13-Watt Spiral-Lite CFL " target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/search?q=EL-13535"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>HERE</strong></span><br></a></span></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<strong></strong><strong> </strong><strong>LED (Light Emitting Diode) </strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>When choosing an LED, it’s best to use an ENERGY STAR ® Qualified bulb. Why? Because ENERGY STAR® works hard to make sure their lamps are energy efficient. According to their website (<a href="http://energystar.gov">energystar.gov</a>) they use at least 75% less energy than incandescent lighting, and they last 35 to 50 times longer than incandescent lighting, and about 2 to 5 times longer than fluorescent lighting. See a full list of our LED Lighting <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><span style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #38761d;"><a style="color: #38761d; text-decoration: underline;" title="LED Bulbs" target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/collections/led-bulbs">HERE</a></span></strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Install Dimmer Switches, and Use Halogen Incandescent Light Bulbs</strong></span>.</p>
<p>Dimmer switches allow you to control how much light output you use. Allow the sun to be your natural light. As the sun starts to set, simply switch your dimmer to get more light from your bulb.</p>
<p>Halogen light bulbs employ a halogen-gas additive that improves lamp life and efficiency. Verbatim makes a Halogen LED that is ENERGY STAR® approved.  <span style="background-color: #ffffff;"><a title="PAR38 LED Lamp ENERGY STAR, 3000K. 1200 lumens, 85W Halogen Replacement, Dimmable" target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/products/par38-led-lamp-energy-star-3000k-1200-lumens-85w-halogen-replacement-dimmable"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0280/3735/files/PAR38_ECO_Left_ES_medium_small.jpg?852"></a></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>You can see a full list of our Halogen Incandescent Light Bulbs <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><span style="color: #38761d;"><a style="color: #38761d; text-decoration: underline;" title="Halogen Bulbs" target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/search?q=halogen+bulb">HERE</a></span></strong></span></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Replace Your Outdoor Lighting</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"></span> Update the look of your home while saving money! Replace your outdoor lighting with decorative LED lighting fixtures<strong>. </strong>We have several options to choose from. Find the one that best suites your style<span style="color: #38761d;"><strong> <a style="color: #38761d;" title="Outdoor LED Lighting" target="_blank" href="http://www.greenlightingwholesale.com/search?q=outdoor+led"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">HERE</span></a></strong></span>  </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Energy isn’t free. Help Mother Earth, while keeping money in your pocket. For all your Green Lighting needs, we are here. “We do not inherit the earth from our ancestors, we borrow it from our children.”<br> <strong>~Native American Proverb</strong></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
